Alexander Franklin

alex-franklin.github.io alexandercreative@gmail.com

646-667-5195

Highlights:

15+ years design and development experience

4 years experience in design teams 2+ years management experience 150+ user feedback interviews

Created, collaborated and updated multiple design systems

Ambassador to engineering, architecture, and project planners/organizers Creates processes to document, understand and support pipeline delivery

Development and leadership background anchors creative decisions and initiatives

Frameworks:

Typescript, Angular, React, Knockout, JQuery and other javascript libraries, D3 and other data visualizations, Bootstrap, Foundation, Visual Studio, Azure, Git, Node

Software:

Adobe XD/Photoshop/Illustrator/Premiere/Acrobat, Pendo, Figma, Campout, Bonfire, Okta, Aha!, VersionOne, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Miro, Google Docs/Slides/Sheets,

Gmail/Calendar

Experience:

WebPTSenior Product Designer - Lead Product Designer

Phoenix, AZ

(03/2020 - Present)

Developed standards and processes for team deliverables and discussions
Rebuilt design library and coordinated ongoing update projects
Introduced Design Briefs and kick-offs to better communicate with other teams
Established institutional knowledge discovery and documentation through workflow validation

Mentored several designers in project planning and management

Created tutorial videos to train other designers in technical creative processes

Created and planned design stories to support engineering roadmap

Became SME in Company's most complex and intricate product Conducted over 100 user feedback sessions to validate product designs

Developed and supported product feature adoption initiatives

Worked directly with developers to create and update reusable UI components Go-to resource for UX consistency and usability questions to keep project planning and

development in motion

ATI Physical Therapy

UX/UI Design and Development Lead

Bolingbrook, IL (05/2016 - 03/2022)

Developed standards for front-end architecture and coding.

Led development team in creating several internal applications spanning PHI, data visualization dashboards, flowsheets, customer intake, scheduling, insurance verfication, patient search and account ledger.

Built component libraries and style guides.

Ambassador in translating business needs into interfaces.

Upgraded/updated legacy software frameworks and interfaces.

Mentored and trained development team in best practices and frameworks.

Alexander Franklin

alex-franklin.github.io alexandercreative@gmail.com 646-667-5195

Experience: ATI Physical Therapy

UX/UI Design and Development Lead

Bolingbrook, IL (05/2016 - 03/2022)

Provide detailed development estimates and accurate timelines to IT leadership. Created mockups, POCs and prototypes to cement solution discovery. Worked with delivery team in creating deployment steps agnostic of environment. Provided detailed unit testing scenarios to QA team to aid in understanding functionality and reducing testing time.

Mirus Research

Normal, IL

User Interface/Interaction Developer

(01/2014 - 05/2016)

Worked with backend programmers in determining proper toolsets for interfacing front and backend data and output.meworks.

Sketched, mockup and prototype user interfaces.

Built and retrofitted responsive interfaces using and extending frontend framework. Maintained team code repositories as the lead front end developer.

Formatted and displayed data from databases using MVC methodology in conjunction with data visualization frameworks.

Documented style and pattern guides detailing the methods used to maintain a consistent frontend codebase.

Utilized Giffy wireframing for sketch layouts.

Consistently delivered integration-ready polished solutions ahead of schedule.

LRS Consulting Services

Peoria, IL

Web Designer/Developer

(05/2013 - 09/2013)

Client: CEFCU, Peoria, IL

Performed updates on intranet and public-facing websites. Created promotional pages in conformance to Visa branding guidelines.

Performed site analysis of CEFCU.com in areas of performance, accessibility, content, typography and layout.

Created interactive web tool that suggests products based on user input. Completed Zend Studio training under the tutelage of Zend expert Adam Culp.

Freelance Graphic/Web Design and Development (12/20107 - 04/2013)

Clients: Baitmaker, Countyline Pub & Grill, Johnny K's Hot Dogs, Yingling Landscaping, Harry Otto Printing Company, JLG Landscaping, Flyware, Reel Pro Video

Provide page mockups using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop CS4

Develop local business website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Test site structure and functionality across all major browsers

Implemented SEO techniques and Google Analytics for tracking and visibility Install and style e-commerce shopping cart

Repair Active Server Page script to restore functionality to shopping cart Install Facebook content mirror for limited client Content Management



alex-franklin.github.io alexandercreative@gmail.com 646-667-5195

Experience: Girl Scouts of Northern Illinois

Elgin, IL

Communications Specialist - Website/Internet Manager

(05/2008 - 11/2012)

Exercised proficiency in Adobe CS4, HTML, CSS, and JS in a WAMP environment Hand-coded urgent and weekly e-newsletter templates
Recorded and edited council video, photography, and audio assets
Administrated and populated council YouTube page with video assets
Ensured optimal web visibility through SEO, Google Analytics, Webmaster Tools
Solely responsible for website maintenance, redesign, and browser compatibility
Provided mockups and user interface testing prior to site and page launches
Worked with Director of Communications to develop branding strategy.

Mindwave Design

Aurora, IL

Intern - Web/Production Designer

(06/2006 - 03/2007)

Developed website mockups and graphics using Adobe CS4, HTML and CSS browser compatibility for several browsers

Education: College for Creative Studies

Detroit, MI

Courseworks towards Bachelor's Degree of Industrial Design

College for Creative Studies Excellence Scholarship
Dean's List Fall 2005

Waubonsee Community College

Sugar Grove, IL

Associate's Degree - Graphic Communication

Dean's List Fall 2002 - Winter 2004, 2008